JULY 23, AFTER 4:00 P.M.
7月23日 16点过后
You'll catch a cold.
会感冒的
The body is in the morgue. Did you contact her parents?
遗体安置在地下室了 要开始联系她父母了吗
Not yet.
还不行
Since a famous author was killed, the press will flood this island.
知名小说家被杀害这种事传出去 媒体会蜂拥到岛上来的
I cannot hide the stab wound on her chest.
她胸口上的刺伤无法隐藏
You don't need to. This is murder, and I know who did it.
不用隐藏了 这就是杀人 犯人也很明确
But... Just give me one more day.
不过还请再给我一天的时间
-Okay. Fine. -Thank you.
-嗯 我知道… -谢谢你
Sorry, you were saying? It's hard to talk with this.
抱歉 打断了你 这样说话好难啊
It's what you said about there being two Shides.
对了 关于你说的 纸垂有两个人这件事
He has lived for over 300 years by transferring bodies.
他可是不断替换肉体 活了300多年的人
I won't be surprised if he had spares for emergencies.
为了以防万一准备了备用的身体 其实也不奇怪
So, Heine gave birth to multiple Shides?
也就是说 波稻生了好几个纸垂？
No.
不 不是这样
Shide preserved his past bodies, but they all burned during the war.
纸垂是将之前用过的肉体都保存起来 不过在先前的战斗中全被烧毁了
My father once told me that.
以前听父亲这么说过
Iwao.
岩…
The body in the photo still exists?
那张照片中的尸体还在
Iwao Karikiri died 40 years ago, after the war.
他之前的肉体 雁切岩 是在40年前死去的 也就是战后
It's a mystery how he preserves or mobilizes the body.
关于遗体的保存方法 以及如何让遗体动起来 都毫无头绪
A second account?
游戏小号？
Cover your ears.
快捂住耳朵
What?
什么
It struck the ocean.
落到海上了
You... How did you know that?
你是怎么知道的
That's what you think now, Sou.
你那是结果论了 窗
It would've taken forever to find shadows if we were together.
如果大家一起行动 就要花多一倍时间搜索影子
Then maybe we might not have saved those three kids.
也许那三个孩子就无法获救了
Hizuru died to save you and Mio. It was Shinpei's choice.
救你和泠 飞鹤注定会死去 这就是慎平的决断
He said it was his responsibility alone.
他说全都是他的责任
He always tries to carry all the weight.
这种时候他总是独自一人承受着一切
It's not just his fault!
这不是你一个人的错
I just want...
我也想…
to help him.
帮他分担啊
We've lost Ushioh, Ms. Nagumo, and Rose.
现在不止是潮 我们还失去了 南云老师 还有罗森
We no longer have Nezu's rifle, Ushioh's shotgun copy,
根津先生的来福枪 潮复制的猎枪 还有凸村先生的手枪 全都没了
But Shide is still alive. What now?
而纸垂却还活着 该怎么办
Do we have a chance to win this?
光凭我们几个 有胜算吗
About that.
关于这个…
What is in your pocket?
你口袋里的是什么
Oh, this?
嗯 这个…
It won't respond to me. It's probably a fragment of Ushioh.
我呼唤过 但没有任何反应 大概是消失的潮留下的碎片
I knew it.
果然…
This is why Heine escaped.
所以波稻才会逃走
What?
什么
It responds, Shinpei. We shadows can sense it.
并非没有反应 小慎 我们影子能感受到
Sis was super mad.
姐姐当时非常生气
When?
什么时候
When Shide threw a knife at you.
纸垂把刀扔向你的时候
Sis is in here.
姐姐就在这里
All her memories are here.
姐姐的记忆全都在这里面
She transferred her memories to this before disappearing.
她应该是在快要消失之前 想办法把记忆转移到这里了
But she has no body. This can't move around.
但是她没有身体 无法行动
That's why Heine thought that Ushioh was still alive.
原来是这样 所以波稻 才误以为潮还活着
She's now just memories, yet she protected you.
就算只剩下记忆 也还是保护了小慎
Can you scan these memories?
贝壳上的记忆呢 你扫描了吗
No, its memories are made so that no one can read them,
不行 这贝壳不让其他影子读取
just like Mother's.
这做法像妈妈一样
Maybe it's because she didn't want the enemy to access it.
应该是不想落入敌人手中才这么做的
So only Sis can read that data.
只有姐姐能读取这里面的数据
But Sis is already...
可是姐姐已经…
She'll be back.
她会回来…
What?
什么
That's right!
对啊
Tomorrow, during the fireworks, at that beach!
明天在烟花升起的时候 她就在那海岸边…
Ushioh before she knew anything will appear again!
那个还什么都不知道的 最初的她会回来
I see.
是吗
We can get her to scan this shell tomorrow.
只要让明天的姐姐扫描这个贝壳
Yes, it'll work. That's why she left this.
嗯 肯定是这样 所以她才会留下贝壳
Ushioh...
潮…
will be reborn!
会复活
Ushio...
潮
We had been pseudo-looping with your memories,
我们通过模拟循环 经历了你和慎平一起循环的记忆
which means Mio saw that scene.
也就是说 泠也看到那个了吧
Sou.
窗
Whoa, M-Mio!
泠
Do you know where Shinpei is?
你知道小慎在哪里吗
Uh, no...
不知道
-Okay. -Wait!
好
What?
怎么了
I...
我…
-I'm still in love with-- -I'm shadow Mio.
还是很喜…
You really won't give up. You already know my answer.
真是执着 你知道我的答案了吧
So, it won't change?
还是一样的答案吗
It won't.
嗯
I see.
是吗
You like Shinpei, don't you?
你喜欢慎平吧？
Ah! W-Why do you say that?
为什么这么说
It's obvious. You're not the shadow.
我早就看出来了 你不是影子吧
You'll stick to your answer?
还是一样吗
Are we still friends?
和我只是朋友吗
Yes.
嗯
And that won't change?
今后也是？
I see. Good.
这样啊 好吧
Shinpei said he was going to the roof.
慎平刚才说 他要去天台上
Shinpei.
小慎
What are you doing?
你在干什么
Practicing.
稍微练习一下
Do you remember what I said when you left this morning?
你还记得吗 你今天早上出门前 我说过的话
You wanted to tell me something.
你说等我平安回来 有话要跟我说吧
Will Sis really come back tomorrow?
明天姐姐真的会回来吗
Ushioh must've put her data in the shell for a reason.
我觉得潮不会无缘无故 把自己的数据存到贝壳里
She may have scanned Shide before she disappeared.
她很可能在消失之前扫描了纸垂
Looks like you've come up with another good strategy.
看样子你又想到好的作战计划了吧
We'll see. I'll tell everyone later. Is this what you wanted to talk about?
我也不知道 待会和大家商量看看 你要说的就是这个吗
Uh, yeah, well...
不是…嗯…
I like you.
喜欢…
R-Really.
你哦
I'm in love you, Shinpei.
我喜欢小慎
Okay.
嗯
That's it?
就这样？
No. Thanks.
那个…谢谢你
Did you know?
该不会你早就发现了？
Yeah.
嗯
Don't be weird about it, okay? I just wanted to get it out there.
不是…你别想多 我只是想说出来而已
We might die tomorrow,
毕竟我们明天或许会死
and I didn't want to go without telling you how I felt.
我才不要抱着还没表白的遗憾死去
I wanted to get it off my chest.
所以我只是想告诉你而已
I see.
这样啊
Yeah.
嗯
Sorry, Mio.
抱歉 泠
I don't feel the same. I love Ushio.
我无法回应你的感情 因为我喜欢潮
Yeah.
嗯
You're my precious little sister.
你是我重要的妹妹
Yeah. Thanks for being honest.
嗯 谢谢你这么明确地告诉我
Ah! I feel so relieved!
舒服多了
Now I can die without any regrets!
这样就算死 我也没有遗憾了
Let it all out, Mio. You were brave.
哭吧 你很了不起哦 泠 被清楚地甩掉了
I'm so proud of you.
我的话 根本说不出口
Tokiko...
朱鹭子
It's okay.
好了
Sis might come back tomorrow, but she's still a shadow.
不过姐姐是影子 明天她也许会回来
She'll disappear once we beat Heine. Can't he get with you then?
但打倒波稻之后 姐姐就会消失
I can't hope for that!
这让我怎么问啦
Shinpei doesn't easily change his mind like that!
小慎才不是那种花心的人
Time to focus! Tomorrow is the big day!
我要调整心情 为了明天
No matter what happens, tomorrow, July 24, is the last day.
无论如何明天…7月24日 一切都会结束的
Shide said that I had the power to observe parallel worlds.
纸垂说过 我有观测平行世界的力量
Parallel worlds?
平行世界？
If a time traveler goes back and changes the future,
可以这么想 时间旅行者一旦回到过去 改变未来
the timeline splits and creates a world parallel to the original one.
时间轴就会出现分支 产生与原本世界相平行的世界
So there's a world where Mio and I die, and another where we live.
你是说 存在我和泠死掉的世界 也存在我们得救的世界对吧？
Yes.
嗯
So when Shinpei dies, the world is copied,
也就是说 慎平哥一旦死去 就会复制粘贴出好几个世界
and only his consciousness moves to one of them.
而慎平哥的意识 会移动到其中一个世界去
Then the past world will be gone.
而在此之前的世界就会随之消失 是这个意思吧？
I get that, but what about Ushioh? How do you know she will appear?
这我明白了 但重点是潮呢 你怎么知道她会出现
Right.
我来说明
I met Ushioh in the third loop and she came with me.
我与潮第一次相遇是在第三轮 不知为何 她会跟随着我
She came to the fourth-loop world with both consciousness and body.
不仅仅是意识 连实体也一起 随着我来到第四轮循环的世界
I see. The fourth-loop world had its own Ushioh,
我知道了 在第四轮的世界中 处于第四轮的潮也是存在的
which means two Ushiohs existed at this point.
包括这个时候 也同时存在两个潮
Exactly.
是的
Right now at this time,
潮此时
Ushioh is floating in the sea.
正在慢慢修复因拯救诗织所受的伤 她应该就在海上漂浮着
If she were like Heine or me,
如果她跟我和波稻一样 那在循环之后
her consciousness would transfer to her body in the sea during a loop.
意识应该会移动到海中的自己身上 可实际上并不是这样
So two Ushiohs exist right now: the ninth-loop Ushioh in the sea,
所以在如今的第九轮中 漂浮在海上的第九轮世界的潮
and the third-loop Ushioh who traveled with me.
以及与我一起进入循环的 第三轮世界的潮是同时存在的
Shide and Heine must be aware of this.
纸垂他们应该也发现了这一点
Ushioh read this in Shide's mind, so she thought of a way to revive herself.
只要读取纸垂的大脑 潮就能想到让自己复活的方法
That's why she left her memories, hoping we would figure this out.
所以她当时才会想办法留下记忆 并且坚信我们会发现
Stop, these are just theories. Just wishful thinking.
喂 这是基于假设的假设吧 这些都只是你的愿望而已
This is the first 24th since we started looping with Ushioh. It's possible.
从慎平与潮一起循环开始 这还是第一次来到24日
I think Ushioh knew.
但是潮自己应该是知道的
How can you be sure?
你为什么这么肯定
It was wishful thinking before, but now I'm certain.
刚才说的是愿望 但现在我确信了
Watch.
你们看
It's moving.
它在动
It's slight, but no matter where I put it, it tries to move south.
虽然动作很小 不过不管放在哪里 它都会朝着南边移动
Since when...
这是什么时候开始的
It moved the most at three this morning, but it's weaker now.
凌晨3点左右 动作最明显 现在已经很微弱了
Oh? The tides!
是因为涨潮吗
Ushioh must be in the Kii Channel, neither in Osaka Bay nor in Setonaikai.
也就是说潮现在不在大阪湾 也不在濑户内海 而是在纪伊水道
Yes. This shell is reacting to Ushioh.
是的 这个贝壳是对潮产生了反应
That means she was close by earlier.
她刚刚来到这附近了
Low tide and high tide occur twice a day.
退潮和涨潮一天各出现两次
The second high tide is around six in the evening.
第二次的涨潮应该就在傍晚6点左右
Then Ushioh will drift closer to this island again.
到时潮就会再次来到这座岛附近
One is already a threat to Shide, yet there may be two Ushiohs.
对于纸垂他们来说 潮本来就是个威胁
He won't risk that. Shide will come at full force.
他们无法忽视这份焦虑 恐怕纸垂本人会全力杀过来
But they don't know Ushioh's exact location.
不过他们不知道潮的准确位置
Heine said that Ushioh was defective, and she couldn't sense her.
波稻曾说过 潮姐姐是残次品 所以无法掌握她的气息
We know where she is. That is our key to victory.
但我们确切掌握了潮的位置 这个差距就是我们制胜的机会
If we miss this chance, we'll lose Ushioh forever.
要是错过了这个机会 我们将会彻底失去潮
Let's go get her.
快去接她吧
Yes.
嗯
I see a glimmer of hope now.
感觉好像看到希望了
Okay, everyone. Let's get moving. We can do this.
那么接下来 请大家按计划行动 拜托了
This mikoshi shrine will be carried to Omotohama Beach.
接下来这个神轿会被抬到万年青沙滩
Load all the collected garbage on it.
请大家将收集来的垃圾都放到神轿上
It may be garbage but it's still divine, so it will be brought back here.
虽说是垃圾 但那也是神的一部分 对吧？
You can walk along this mikoshi, then enjoy the Omiokuri.
-跟着神轿一起游行 -是鲸鱼
Hiruko will bring you good health.
这样大家就会受到蛭子大人的庇护 健康运势暴涨
At night, we can enjoy the fireworks.
另外推荐大家来这院内观看烟花表演 可以看得很清楚哦
Longevity to all of us, you and me!
大家和我一起长命百岁吧
It's quiet.
好安静啊
Yes. It's been quiet. Shinpei's strategy must be working.
嗯 安静了好一阵子 说明慎平先生的作战计划很顺利吧
Yeah.
嗯
I didn't think we'd talk again, Ryunosuke.
没想到还能像这样和你说上话啊 龙之介
Sis was grateful to you.
姐姐很感谢根津先生您
What?
什么
You saved her 14 years ago.
感谢您在14年前救了她
Hizuru wrote to me sometimes.
我时不时会收到飞鹤寄来的信
I was shocked when she said her novel became a movie.
听说她写的书拍成了电影时 我真是惊呆了
I didn't even know she was an author.
我还说她怎么都不先告诉我 自己当上小说家的事
You were really the only person who knew that.
在现实生活中 知道这件事的 也只有根津先生您
What's with her? Was she shy?
那丫头干什么啊 害羞吗
You're the only adult who believed her story about shadows.
因为根津先生是唯一一个 相信影子的存在
Because of that, people thought I was crazy.
就是因为这样 连我也被当成怪人了
I guess I'm used to that, though.
不过我也都习惯了
We trust you, Mr. Nezu. Both Sis and me.
我们都很信任根津先生 姐姐和我都是
You don't need to say that.
事到如今 我们之间已经不需要言语了
It's time.
来了
A festival without Ushio seems so somber.
没有小潮在 庆典都显得冷清了
She was always leading the mikoshi.
她总是冲在前头帮忙抬神轿的
I'll carry it for the both of us.
我会替她出那份力的
Stay until the end this year, Alain.
今年你一定要 从头到尾都参加啊 艾伦
You know I'd love to, but I have to prep for tomorrow.
我也想啊 不过我还要回去 做明天开店的准备
Tomorrow?
明天？
What is it?
怎么了
Nothing. I hadn't planned for tomorrow.
没什么 我只是没考虑过明天的事
In the search of the Kii Channel, are any strays ignoring my signal?
搜索纪伊水道的影子当中 有没有无视我信号的野生影子
Why do you ask?
什么意思
Two hours have passed since I lost Shinpei's location.
慎平的位置已经消失了快半小时 对于这点你怎么看 纸垂
Did he erase the mark?
那个手印被抹除了？
No. It can't be erased. I burned it onto his very presence.
不 手印不会消失的 那是对慎平的存在本身做的印记
However, he can block his presence, just like you in the mud.
不过存在本身是可以隔绝的 只要像你一样包裹在泥里
I gave him too many ideas.
看来提示似乎给得太多了
Most strays were sent to find Ushioh. If Hiruko's grotto is invaded now...
大多数野生影子都去搜索潮了 如果现在蛭子洞被他们攻破…
That won't happen yet.
不 暂时还不会
They came to my burrow once, and nearly got destroyed.
那些人曾经来过我休息的地方一次 差点全军覆没
They won't attempt it again, unless they are certain.
除非有十足的把握 否则他们不会再次攻进那里的
Then why hide?
那到底是为什么要藏起来呢
Here is my theory. It's the Ushioh he has with him.
接下来的只是我的推测 如果说只有紧跟慎平的潮
It can sense Ushioh's location in the Kii Channel.
知道漂浮在纪伊水道中的自己 所处的位置呢
He is hiding his own location,
为了先我们一步找到潮
so that he can get to Ushioh without revealing her position.
他隐藏了自己的位置 避免让我们掌握潮的位置
I would do that if I were him.
如果是我 就会这么做
Find Ushioh before they do and get rid of her.
找到潮 抢在他们前面把潮干掉
Be fruitful.
不胜惶恐 谨以此言 祈求伊邪那岐大神
In the open fields of Kyushu, Miyasaki, Tachibana,
于筑紫之日向 橘之小户之阿波岐原
the purification shall occur.
行禊祓之仪时 降临于世之祓户大神等
-Heave ho!
嘿哟
Cast away the disaster, famine, and destruction.
-愿将诸多灾祸 罪孽 污秽 -嘿哟
-Cast away, purify, light the way... -Step back!
-予以拔除 予以净化 祈求神明… -往后退
Shide, you hide leaves in a forest.
纸垂啊 俗话说 藏叶于林
Shinpei will come, hidden among strays.
慎平一定会来的 你就藏在野生影子当中吧
I told the strays to go near you.
我会让野生影子们聚集在你身边
Look around. Find a stray separated from the flock.
仔细观察周围 找出离群的那个
Found you.
找到了
One stray is drifting away into the sea.
有一个野生的朝海那边去了
She's really close. I'm getting stronger responses.
很近 很近了 反应越来越激烈
He found me.
被发现了
Hurry, Gil!
加快速度 吉尔
There.
在那
I found her!
找到了
I'm coming, Ushioh!
我这就过去 潮
So dark. I can't see anything.
好黑 什么都看不到
Where am I?
这里是什么地方
What was I doing?
我刚才在做什么来着
Shinpei?
慎平？
You really won't go to say goodbye?
你真的不去送行吗
Shinpei is leaving.
小慎要走了哦
Let him!
都说了我不去
I don't care about him anymore.
我再也不管他那种家伙了
Wait. No, don't go!
等等 不是的 不要走
Shinpei... I miss you.
慎平 我好想你
Ushioh!
潮
Huh? Who's that?
是谁…
Is someone calling me?
是在叫我吗
Ushioh!
潮
Shinpei?
慎平？
Wh-What the heck? Whoa!
那是什么啊
A-A baby? What are you? Where'd you come from?
婴儿？你是谁 哪家的孩子
Got you.
抓到你了
Why are you here? Shinpei? You came back?
你怎么会在这里 慎平 你回来了吗
Yes.
嗯
I came to get you.
我来接你回去了
What?
什么
I remember now. I knew you'd come through!
我想起来了 我就知道你一定能做到
Yep.
嗯
Ushioh! Don't let them grab us!
潮 千万别被它们抓住了
No worries! Piece of cake!
放心吧 我完全彻底地…
I'm back and better than ever!
复活啦